<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on Vikram Mandyam</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/categories/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on Vikram Mandyam</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vikram-mandyam.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The books of the year 2023</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2024/02/03/the-books-of-the-year-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2024/02/03/the-books-of-the-year-2023/</guid><description>I read 51 books in 2023. It was a good year of reading once again, and I say that with more gratitude than pride. I’ve been doing end-of-the-year book lists for 4 years now. You can read my previous lists here: 2022 , 2021 , 2020 , 2019 .
A lot of reading this year was fiction, and many of the philosophy and technical books were re-reads. Both of these genres have a lot of original books that are seminal and a lot of books that rehash and detail the same concepts.</description></item><item><title>The books of the year 2022</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2023/01/03/the-books-of-the-year-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2023/01/03/the-books-of-the-year-2022/</guid><description>2022 has been a year of ups and downs for the world at large, and it has left me (and many others, I’d guess) with a looming sense of unpredictability. Through it all, reading has anchored me like nothing else.
I’ve been doing end-of-the-year book lists for 3 years now. You can read my previous lists here: 2021 , 2020 , 2019 .
Overall, I read 56 books this year , and here is a look at my favorite of the lot</description></item><item><title>The books of the year 2021</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2022/01/02/the-books-of-the-year-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2022/01/02/the-books-of-the-year-2021/</guid><description>It is that time of the year again when social media will be rife with lists-of-the-year posts. The lists could be about videos, podcasts, movies, etc. I’ve been doing end-of-the-year book lists for 2 years now. You can read my previous lists here: 2020 , 2019 . So I asked myself, Should I write one this year too? I realized the answer to that lay in the more intriguing question: Why am I doing this?</description></item><item><title> What I learned from the book "The innovation stack"</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2021/12/05/what-i-learned-from-the-book-the-innovation-stack/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2021/12/05/what-i-learned-from-the-book-the-innovation-stack/</guid><description>.org-center { margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center; } Photo from the book&amp;rsquo;s Amazon.in page Introduction I recently read a fascinating book by Jim McKelvey called &amp;ldquo;The Innovation Stack&amp;rdquo;. It is about the origin story of &amp;ldquo;Square&amp;rdquo; - the &amp;ldquo;payments startup&amp;rdquo;. Although this book is the story of Square, it is actually much more - part philosophy, part biography, part business book.
Here is my summary of it.</description></item><item><title>Books I read in 2020</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2021/01/05/books-i-read-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2021/01/05/books-i-read-in-2020/</guid><description>.org-center { margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center; } Photo by Oladimeji Ajegbile from Pexel 2020 has been a tough year for everyone. It has been said so many times that it has become a cliché. I only bring this up because the first book I read in 2020 was on an airplane - back when &amp;ldquo;travel&amp;rdquo; was not a dreaded word. It almost feels alien, like a world that only ever existed in a dream!</description></item><item><title>Staying in the game</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2020/04/20/staying-in-the-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2020/04/20/staying-in-the-game/</guid><description>.org-center { margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center; } Photo by freddie marriage on Unsplash I recently read the book “The infinite game” by Simon Sinek . While it is a business book, it has some relevant insights for the times we’re seeing now.
Finite and infinite games The author talks about two types of games - finite games and infinite games. An example of a finite game is tennis.</description></item><item><title>My year 2019 in books</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2019/12/31/my-year-2019-in-books/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2019/12/31/my-year-2019-in-books/</guid><description>.org-center { margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center; } Photo by Iñaki del Olmo on Unsplash I’ve often felt that the dreaded drive to office is a massive waste of human potential. I am thankful for a job that allows me to carpool, so I can spend this time reading. For me, the greatest joy in reading comes from a sensation of time-dilation and flow.
The 28 books I read this year This year has been a good one for my reading.</description></item><item><title> "Designing data-intensive applications"​ By Martin Kleppmann: A summary</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2018/09/21/designing-data-intensive-applications-by-martin-kleppmann-a-summary/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2018/09/21/designing-data-intensive-applications-by-martin-kleppmann-a-summary/</guid><description>I recently finished reading the book &amp;ldquo;Designing data-intensive applications” , written by Martin Kleppmann . It took me a little over a year to finish reading this end-to-end, but it has been well worth the time!
This is a very good book to get a clear picture of the landscape of data systems. It will provide you with enough details to figure out the right data approach for your project no matter what the scale of the project is.</description></item></channel></rss>