<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Philosophy on Vikram Mandyam</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/categories/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Philosophy on Vikram Mandyam</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vikram-mandyam.com/categories/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vedanta-Buddha-Goggins</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2025/02/05/vedanta-buddha-goggins/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2025/02/05/vedanta-buddha-goggins/</guid><description>.org-center { margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center; } .org-center { margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center; } Photo by abhijeet gourav on Unsplash Mastering the Mind, Conquering Cheap Dopamine and some self-discipline tips Lately, I have been pondering about mental mastery, specifically on avoiding distractions and cheap dopamine. When I get into a serious pondering mood, I dive deep into the rabbit hole. I usually look at multiple approaches and try to tailor it to suit my needs.</description></item><item><title>Good news, Bad news, Who Knows?</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2022/08/07/good-news-bad-news-who-knows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2022/08/07/good-news-bad-news-who-knows/</guid><description>.org-center { margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center; } .org-center { margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center; } Photo by Fabian Burghardt on Unsplash Albert Einstein once said - &amp;ldquo;The most important decision we make is whether we believe we live in a friendly or a hostile universe.&amp;rdquo;
How you view your world - as good or as bad, impacts your attitude towards situations.
A good parable that explains this, is that of a Chinese farmer.</description></item><item><title>The wolf you feed</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2022/05/06/the-wolf-you-feed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2022/05/06/the-wolf-you-feed/</guid><description>.org-center { margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center; } .org-center { margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center; } Photo by M. Zonderling on Unsplash It is inevitable that all of us will face difficulties and challenges as we go through our lives. A beloved family member may fall sick, we will fall sick ourselves, we will not make a team that we so desperately wanted to and worked hard for.</description></item><item><title>A Daily Pact With Philosophy</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2021/10/23/a-daily-pact-with-philosophy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2021/10/23/a-daily-pact-with-philosophy/</guid><description>Almost everybody complains that life is too busy, stressful, meaningless, unsatisfactory etc&amp;hellip; The mental chatter in our heads affects how we think, feel and act and this chatter is usually negative. We ruminate on the past, worry about the future or lament the present.
All of us search for those moments when we feel extremely peaceful and calm. This usually happens when we are at vacation, or just doing nothing. The reason we feel calm when we are at vacation is that there is nothing to immediately worry about and the mental chatter, occupies a pleasant space.</description></item></channel></rss>