<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software on Vikram Mandyam</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/categories/software/</link><description>Recent content in Software on Vikram Mandyam</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vikram-mandyam.com/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>"Designing data-intensive applications"​ By Martin Kleppmann: A summary</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2018/09/21/designing-data-intensive-applications-by-martin-kleppmann-a-summary/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2018/09/21/designing-data-intensive-applications-by-martin-kleppmann-a-summary/</guid><description>I recently finished reading the book &amp;ldquo;Designing data-intensive applications” , written by Martin Kleppmann . It took me a little over a year to finish reading this end-to-end, but it has been well worth the time!
This is a very good book to get a clear picture of the landscape of data systems. It will provide you with enough details to figure out the right data approach for your project no matter what the scale of the project is.</description></item><item><title>Explain in simple terms: Unicode</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2020/11/15/explain-in-simple-terms-unicode/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2020/11/15/explain-in-simple-terms-unicode/</guid><description>Unicode is an important area that programmers needs to know, particularly if one is doing some form of text processing and/or internationalization and localization. Even if you are a seasoned coder, you may feel like you&amp;rsquo;re on thin ice with Unicode.
Some weeks ago, I tried to get to the bottom of Unicode, and I&amp;rsquo;m writing this article to document my understanding of it.
Common terms First, let us look at some terms which are commonly known, but may not be as well understood.</description></item><item><title>Learning is the constraint</title><link>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2021/04/05/learning-is-the-constraint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vikram-mandyam.com/posts/2021/04/05/learning-is-the-constraint/</guid><description>TIL about &amp;ldquo;Learning is the constraint&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;
In software teams, that need to deliver good results fast, every person in the team needs to learn fast and invest in learning to be a fast learner!
Quoting from the really insightful article :
&amp;ldquo;Think of a recent significant project or piece of work your team completed How long did it take, end to end, inception to delivery? Now imagine you were to do the same project over again, with the same team, the same organizational constraints, the same everything, except your team would already know everything they learned during the project.</description></item></channel></rss>